Warren S. McCulloch Papers 1860s-1987 Mss.B.M139
American Philosophical Society
- Series II. Professional Papers, 1939-1970; 33 lin. feet (Box 29-61)
  - MIT. Research Laboratory for Electronics. Neurophysiology. Quarterly Progress Report, No. 81, April 15, 1966, 1 item
  - MIT. Research Laboratory for Electronics. Neurophysiology. Quarterly Progress Report, No. 82, July 15, 1966, 1 item
  - MIT. Research Laboratory for Electronics. Neurophysiology. Quarterly Progress Report, No. 83, October 15, 1966, 1 item
  - MIT. Research Laboratory for Electronics. Neurophysiology. Quarterly Progress Report, No. 84, January 15, 1967, 1 item
  - MIT. Research Laboratory for Electronics. Neurophysiology. Quarterly Progress Report, No. 85, April 15, 1967, 1 item
  - MIT. Research Laboratory for Electronics. Neurophysiology. Quarterly Progress Report, No. 86, July 15, 1967, 1 item
  - MIT. Research Laboratory for Electronics. Neurophysiology. Quarterly Progress Report, No. 87, October 15, 1967, 1 item
  - MIT. Research Laboratory for Electronics. Neurophysiology. Quarterly Progress Report, No. 88, January 15, 1968, 1 item
  - MIT. Research Laboratory for Electronics. Neurophysiology. Quarterly Progress Report, No. 91, October 15, 1968, 1 item
  - MIT. Research Laboratory for Electronics. Neurophysiology. Quarterly Progress Report, No. 92, January 15, 1969, 1 item
  - MIT. Research Laboratory for Electronics. Neurophysiology. Quarterly Progress Report, No. 93, April 15, 1969, 1 item
  - MIT. Research Laboratory for Electronics. Neurophysiology. Quarterly Progress Report, [no number, n.d.], 1 item
  - MIT. Research Laboratory of Electronics. General summary of work by neurophysiology group..., 1954; 3 items
  - MIT. Revision of I.O. Machines, 1968; 1 item
  - Montefiori Hospital (Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1955; 3 items
  - National Academy of Sciences. Science in Space. Chptrs. 1-4, 1960-1961; 4 items
  - National Academy of Sciences. Science in Space. Chptrs. 5-7, 1960; 3 items
  - National Academy of Sciences. Science in Space. Chptrs. 8-9, 1960; 2 items
  - NASA, 1961-1968; 27 items
  - NASA. Committee on biotechnology and human research 1964 July. #1, 5 items
  - NASA. Committee on biotechnology and human research 1964 July. #2, 1 item
  - NASA. Committee on biotechnology and human research 1964 July. #3, 6 items
  - NASA. Committee on biotechnology and human research 1964 November #1, 1 item
  - NASA. Committee on biotechnology and human research 1964 November #2, 5 items
  - NASA. Committee on biotechnology and human research 1965 March #1, 1 item
  - NASA. Committee on biotechnology and human research 1965 March #2, 2 items
  - NASA. Committee on biotechnology and human research1965 March #3, 1964-1965; 22 items
  - NASA. Job #1, 1964; 28 items
  - NASA. Job #2, 1963-1964; 6 items
  - NASA. Minutes of Research Advisory Committee. #1, 1964; 4 items
  - NASA. Minutes of Research Advisory Committee. #2, 1964; 10 items
  - NASA. Space biology program, n.d.; 1 item
  - National Electronics Conference, Inc., 1948-1949; 7 items
  - National Institute of Health #1, 1952-1964; 17 items
  - National Institute of Health #2, 1952-1959; 6 items
  - National Institute of Health Recommendations, 1966; 2 items
  - National Program in Space Biology, 1959-1964; 1 item
  - National Science Foundation #1, 1958; 25 items
  - National Science Foundation #2, 1955; 10 items
  - National Science Foundation. Proposal., 1954-1965; 8 items
  - National Science Foundation. Report., 1957-1958; 6 items
  - National Science Foundation. Reports to, 1955; 1 item
  - National Science Foundation. Reviewed proposals, 1960-1967; 27 items
  - Nervous nets that rede invariants by scanning groups, n.d.; 1 item
  - Neuropsychiatry, 1969; 1 item
  - Neurosciences Research Program, 1964; 9 items
  - New York Academy of Sciences #1, 1958-1968; 40 item
  - New York Academy of Sciences #2, 1959-1964; 11 items
  - New York Academy of Sciences #3, 1942-1966; 194 items
  - New York Academy of Sciences Money soliciting, n.d.; 1 item
  - Notes #1, 1953-1966; 11 item
  - Notes #2, n.d.; 2 items
  - Of minding and nothing, 1 item
  - Ohio State University., 1962; 11 item
  - On Dr. Alexander's paper, 1943; 1 item
  - On Dr. Masserman's paper., 1943; 1 item
  - Oneirophrenia, n.d.; 1 item
  - ORCA, 1969; 10 items
  - Photographs, n.d.; 16 items
  - Physical environment unit #1, 1945-1946; 40 items
  - Physical environment unit #2, 1941-1944; 36 items
  - Physical environment unit #1, 1943; 51 item
  - Physical environment unit #2, 1944-1947; 25 items
  - Physiology and "psychichic" regression, 1 item
  - Poetry letters, 1959-1960; 40 items
  - Potential changes of the cord during bulbo reticular inhibition of the 2 neuron arc, 1950; 1 item
  - A preference for related areas, n.d.; 1 item
  - Preliminary proposal for TV camera and information processor for Voyager, 1965; 1 item
  - Presentation of Baily's paper..., n.d.; 4 items
  - Presented to math. biophysics, 1943; 1 item
  - Problem in genetics, n.d.; 1 item
  - Progress report, American Foundation for the Blind, Inc., 1960-1962; 2 items
  - Proposal for development of electronic computers with properties of a primate brain, 1965; 1 item
  - Proposal for funds, 1965; 1 item
  - Proposal for study of effect of ultrasound on nerve tissue, 1950-1951; 4 items
  - Proposals..., n.d.; 3 items
  - Public Health Service. Grant, 1955-1968; 6 items
  - Publications #1, 1959-1968; 49 items
  - Publications #2, 1967-1969; 15 items
  - Publications #3, 1967-1969; 28 items
  - Publications #4, 1962-1968; 45 items
  - Ramo task force, 1967-1969; 35 items
  - Ramon y Cajal, an appreciation, 1963; 3 items
  - Ravello Summer School of Physics, 2nd, 1967; 4 items
  - Reliable computation in the presence of noise, n.d.; 2 items
  - Report of the panel on bioastronautics, 1962; 2 items
  - Reprint requests #1, 1957-1958; 30 items
  - Reprint requests #2, 1956-1958; 48 items
  - Reprint requests #3, 1951-1952; 30 items
  - Reprint requests #4, 1952-1953; 35 items
  - Reprint requests #5, 1967-1969; 187 items
  - Reprint requests, 1949, 123 items
  - Reprint requests, 1950 #1, 143 items
  - Reprint requests, 1950 #2, 56 items
  - Reprint requests, 1951 #1, 55 items
  - Reprint requests, 1951 #2, 30 items
  - Reprint requests, 1952 #1, 26 items
  - Reprint requests, 1952 #2, 27 items
  - Reprint requests, 1953, 24 items
  - Reprint requests, 1954 #1, 1953-1954; 31 item
  - Reprint requests, 1954 #2, 1953-1954; 37 items
  - Reprint requests, 1955, 32 items
  - Reprint requests, 1959 - 1961 #1, 1959-1960; 34 items
  - Reprint requests, 1959 - 1961 #2, 1959-1960; 31 item
  - Reprint requests, 1959 - 1961 #3, 1960-1961; 98 items
  - Reprint requests, 1962 - 1963 #1, 1956-1963; 50 items
  - Reprint requests, 1962 - 1963 #2, 1960-1963; 95 items
  - Reprints "Carbohydrate Metabolism" sent out, 1964-1968; 80 items
  - Research in cybernetics in U.S. educational systems, 1963; 112 items
  - Research questions, 1959-1960; 7 items
  - Review: of Petrie's book, 1968; 41 item
  - Royal Society of Medicine of London, 1948-1949; 9 items
  - St. Elizabeth's Hospital Society (Washington, D.C.), 1950; 7 items
  - Science, 1958-1962; 15 items
  - Science - Reviews, 1968; 3 items
  - Science et Vie, No. 496, 1959; 1 item
  - Seminars, 1950; 10 items
  - Sherwood, Steven. Patient Records #1 [RESTRICTED]
  - Sherwood, Steven. Patient Records #2 [RESTRICTED]
  - Sherwood, Steven. Research Records
  - Sigma Xi, 1952; 42 items
  - Simulation of information processing in a neuron, 1964; 1 item
  - Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine, 1945-1951; 9 items
  - Society for General Systems Research, 1959; 1 item
  - Society for Neurophysiology, 1939; 2 items
  - Society of Physiological Neurology, 1939-1942; 50 items
  - Sociological material, 1941-1950; 14 items
  - Some observations on experimentally produced convulsions, n.d.; 1 item
  - Some peoples and groups working in cybernetics, 1963; 2 items
  - Speech, n.d.; 1 item
  - Stereotaxic instrument for monkey and cat, 1 item
  - Teagle Foundation, Inc. #1, 1958-1966; 52 items
  - Teagle Foundation, Inc. #2, 1954-1955; 7 items
  - Teagle Foundation, Inc. #3, 1954; 1 item
  - Teagle Foundation, Inc. #4, 1952-1953; 40 items
  - Teagle Foundation, Inc. Reports to..., 1954-1956; 8 items
  - Technical Report no. 276 - requests to reprint, 1954; 2 items
  - Thalamotomy, n.d.; 1 item
  - Thales "Through the Den" (correspondence), 1951-1952; 7 items
  - Theory or stability in biological systems, 1958-1969; 2 items
  - Thermo-coagulation experiments..., 1937-1938; 12 items
  - Tractatus, 1946; 4 items
  - Tractatus Neurologico-logicus, 1946; 1 item
  - Travel, 1960; 12 items
  - Travel: Europe #1, 1953; 34 items
  - Travel: Europe #2, 1953; 81 item
  - Travel: Foreign, 1949-1951; 28 items
  - Travel: Peru, 1967; 4 items
  - Travel: Peru-Venezuela #1, 1967; 8 items
  - Travel: Peru-Venezuela #2, 1967; 9 items
  - Travel: Report of a trip to London
  - Travel: Visit to Ames Laboratory., 1961; 1 item
  - Travel: Visit to Goddart Space Center., 1961; 1 item
  - Travel: Visit to the Lawrence Radiation Laboratory., 1961; 1 item
  - Travels #1, 1957-1962; 46 items
  - Travels #2, 1949; 14 items
  - Travels #3, 1949; 35 items
  - Treasure Trove, 1954-1955; 2 items
  - Tzannes. Concept of "meaning" in information theory, 1968; 1 item
  - United Aircraft, 1963-1966; 6 items
  - United States Air Force contract termination, 1965; 5 items
  - United States Air Force. Directorate of Information Sciences, 1962; 2 items
  - United States Navy. Naval Medical Research Laboratory. Annual report, 1960; 1 item
  - United States Navy. Naval Medical Research Laboratory. Current program of research, 1961; 1 item
  - United States Navy. Naval Medical Research Laboratory. History., 1959-1960; 1 item
  - United States Navy. Naval Medical Research Laboratory. Relationship of diurnal cycles..., 1960; 1 item
  - United States Navy. Office of Naval Research #1, 1949-1952; 6 items
  - United States Navy. Office of Naval Research #2, 1961-1965; 13 items
  - United States Navy. Office of Naval Research. Cambridge and Oxford, 1 item
  - United States Navy. Office of Naval Research. London #1, 1953; 6 items
  - United States Navy. Office of Naval Research. London #2, 1953; 16 items
  - United States Navy. Office of Naval Research. London #3, 1953-1955; 12 items
  - United States Navy. Office of Naval Research. London #4, 1953-1956; 11 item
  - United States Navy. Office of Naval Research. London #5, 1953; 5 items
  - United States Navy. Office of Naval Research. Psychology
  - United States Navy. Office of Naval Research. Travel #1, 1963-1968; 12 items
  - United States Navy. Office of Naval Research. Travel #2, 1964-1968; 11 item
  - United States Navy. Progress report, Navy contract, 1950; 3 items
  - University of California, Los Angeles, 1960-1964; 38 items
  - University of California, Los Angeles. Modern engineering course. Crotonville. #1, 1962; 18 items
  - University of California, Los Angeles. Modern engineering course. Crotonville. #2, 1962; 1 item
  - University of California, Los Angeles. Modern engineering course. Crotonville. #3, 1961-1962; 21 item
  - University of Illinois. Biological Computer Laboratory. Cybernetics directory, 1966; 1 item
  - University of Tennessee, 1968; 2 items
  - WADD Proposal., 1960; 1 item
  - Why the mind is in the head (correspondence), 1951; 9 items
  - Winter Haven Lions Research Foundation #1, 1961-1963; 21 item
  - Winter Haven Lions Research Foundation #2, 1961; 7 items
  - World is all that is the case, n.d.; 1 item
  - Zest and carbo-hydrate metabolism, 1950; 13 items
- Series III. Works by Warren S. McCulloch, 1921-1982; 4.25 lin. feet (Box 62-70)
  Works written by McCulloch and in collaboration with colleagues. Material includes correspondence relating to the works, drafts, and offprints of the published works.
  - "1967 Automata Model of Man - MESM Unvield.", 1967; n.d.; 2 items; Arthur Iberall
  - "1967 Behavioral Model of Man. His Chains Revealed", 1968; 1 item; Arthur Iberall
  - "About McCarthy", n.d.; 2 items
    Introduction to "Of I and It"
  - "Abracadabra", 1961; 1 item
  - "Action Potentials of the Cerebral Cortex and Spinal Cord Before and After Cortical Stimulation", 1936; 1 item; J. G. Dusser de Barenne
  - "Action Potentials of Various Layers of the Cerebral Cortex of the Monkey", 1935; 1 item; J. G. Dusser de Barenne
  - "Actitivity in the Great Superficial Petrosal Nerve Influencing the Electroencephalogram", 1944; 1 item; John B. Green
  - "After-Dinner Address: The Fun of Failures", 1969; 1 item; Seymour Papert, Manuel Blum, Jose L. S. Da Fonesca, and Roberto Moreno-Diaz
  - "Agathe Tyche: Of Nervous Nets - the Lucky Reckoners", 1958; 14 items
  - "Anastomatic Nets Combatting Noise", 1962; n.d.; 2 folders
  - "Anatomical and Physiological Considerations in ...", 1941; 1 item
    Lecture at the University of Illinois College of Medicine
  - "Anatomy and Physiology of Vision in the Frog (Rana pipiens), 1960; 1 item; Humberto R. Maturana, J. Y. Lettvin, and W. H. Pitts
  - "Aviation in Medicine", 1945; 1 item
  - "Background", 2 items
    Talk about neurons
  - "The Beginning of Cybernetics", 1969-1970; 4 folders
  - "Bibliography for M90", 1947 or 1948; 1 item
    Course bibliography
  - "Biological Computers", 1958; 1 item
    Lecture, University of Illinois
  - "Biological Computers", 1957; 5 items
    Lecture, University of Pittsburg
  - "The Biological Sciences", 1966; 1 item; Warren M. Brodey
    From The Great Ideas Today 1966
  - Book review, Brains, Machines, and Mathematics by M. A. Arbib, 1964; 1 item
  - Book review, Design for a Brain, 1953; 16 items
    Review published in Scientific American
  - Book review, Design for a Brain by W. Ross Ashby, [1956 or 1957]; 1 item
  - Book review, An Introduction to Cybernetics by W. Ross Ashby, 1957; 1 item
  - Book review, The Memory System of the Brain by J. Z. Young, 1967; 1 item
  - "Brain, A Computer with a Negative Feedback", 1955-1958; 1 item
    Lecture, Institute of Radio Engineers National Convention, 1955
  - "The Brain as Computing Machine", 1949; 1 item
  - "A Brief Insulin Tolerance Test.", 1947; 18 items; G. J. Kronenberg
  - "Calcolatrici Biologiche", n.d.; 1 item
  - "Central Effects of Strychnine on Spinal Afferent Fibers", 1955; 1 item; J. Y. Lettvin, W. Pitts, and P. D. Wall
  - "Central Nervous System", 1943; 1 item
    Summary of Lectures
  - "The Central Somaesthetic Nervous System", n.d.; 1 item
    Printed in Encyclopedia Britannica
  - "A Cerebello-Bulbo-Reticular Pathway for Suppression", 1949; 2 items; Ray S. Snider and H. W. Magoun
    Extensive draft with drawings and photographs and an offprint
  - "Changes of Hydrogen Ion Concentration of the Cerebral Cortex", 1937; 1 item; J. G. Dusser de Barenne and Leslie F. Nims
  - "Changes of Noble-Metal Electrode EMF of Cerebral Cortex.", 1945; 5 items; C. Goodwin and J. R. Klein
  - "The Chicago Period", n.d.; 1 item
  - "Circularities in Nets and the Concept of Functional Matrices", 1 item; Roberto Moreno-Diaz
  - "The Colloquy of Living Things", 1963; 1 item
    Printed in Bio-Telemetry 1963
  - "The Command and Control System of the Vertebrates", 1965; 1 item; W. L. Kilmer
  - "Commentary", [1965?]
  - "Comment Les Structures Nerveuses ont des Idees", n.d.; 1 item
  - "Committee on Mathematical Biology", 1956; 1 item
    Letter of protest about reductions in the Committee
  - "Une Comparison entre les Machines a Calculer et les Cerveau", 1953; 1 item; J. Y. Lettvin, W. H. Ptts, and P. C. Dell
  - "The Computer and the Brain.", 1968; 1 item
    Not used nor published, 1968 ACA
  - "Cones, Knots, Fronds, and Ions", 1965
  - "A Confession of Ignorance", 1952; 1 item
    From The Biology of Mental Health and Disease, for the Twenty-seventh Annual Conference of the Milbank Memorial Fund.
  - "Control of Posture and Motion", 1969; 1 item
  - "Cortical Origin and Distribution of Corpus Callosum and Anterior Commissure in the Monkey (Macaca Mulatta)", 1941; 1 item; Garol, Hugh W.
  - "Cortical Origin and Distribution of Corpus Callosum and Anterior Commissure in Chimpanzee (Pan Satyrus)", 1941; 1 item; H. W. Garol and P. Bailey
  - "A Cortico-Bulbo-Reticular Pathway from Area 4-s", 1946; 1 item; S., C. Graf and H. W. Magoun
  - "Cortico-Cortical Connections", n.d.; 1 item
  - Critique of Josiah Macy Jr. Foundation conferences, 1969; 5 items
  - "Cybernetic Problems of Learning", 1967; 1 item
  - [Cybernetics in Russia], [1964?]; 2 items
  - "Dans L'Antre du Métaphysicien", 1951; 1 item
  - "Designated Discussion", 1958; 1 item
  - "Dialogue", n.d.; 1 item
  - "The Direct Functional Interrelation of Sensory Cortex and Optic Thalamus", 1938; 1 item; J. G. Dusser de Barenne
  - "Discussion", n.d.; 1 item
  - "Dog's Blood-Sugar Level Affected by Taste and Sham-Feeding", 1951-1952; 7 items; E. Ridley, I.A. Share, and J.M. Berry
  - Dr. McCulloch's Discussion of Dr. Masserman's paper, 1943; 1 item
  - "Dynamic Symmetry", 1921; 4 folders
    Notes and graphs on experiments
  - "Effects of Intraventricular Acetylcholine and Cholinesterase and Related Compounds in Normal and 'Catatonci' Cats", 1951; 1 item; Stephen Sherwood and Ellen Ridley
  - "An Electrical Hypothesis of Central Inhibition and Facilitation", 1951-1952; 3 folders; Jerome Y. Lettvin and W.H. Pitts.
  - "Electrical Signs of Remote Events in the Central Nervous System", 1949; 1 item
  - "Embodiment of a Plastic Concept of the Reticular Formation.", 1968; 1 item; W. L. Kilmer and J. Blum.
  - "An Embodiment of Some Vertebrate Command and Control Principles", 1968; 2 items; W. L. Kilmer and J. Blum.
  - "Embodiments of Mind", 1965-1968; 3 folders
  - "Engineering Bionics. Ad Hoc Review Committee Report", 1965; 1 item
  - "Eulogy for Lawrence Kubie", 1968; 2 items
  - "Evidence That Cut Optic Nerve Fibers in a Frog Regenrate to Their Proper Places in the Tectum", 1959; 1 item; Humberto R. Maturana, J. Y. Lettvin, and W. H. Pitts
  - "Excitability of Cerebral Cortex in Infant Macaca Mulatta", 1942; 1 item; Margaret Kennard
  - "Excitability Changes in Anatomical Components of the Monosynaptic Arc Following Tetanic Stimulation", 1956; 1 item; McCulloch, et al
  - "Exitus Acta Non Probat", 1958; 1 item
    Lecture, Physiological Society meeting
  - "Experimental Production of Tremor in the Monkey", n.d.; 8 items; A. A. Ward and H. W. Magoun
  - "An Explanation of Irreversibility of Reflex Action", n.d.; 1 item
  - "Extinction as a Cortical Phenomenon", 1936; 1 item; J. G. Dusser de Barenne
    Russian offprint in English
  - "Extinction: Local Stimulatory Inactivation Within the Motor Cortex", 1935; 1 item; J. G. Dusser de Barenne
  - "An 'Extinction' Phenomenon on Stimulation of the Cerebral Cortex", 1934; 1 item; J. G. Dusser de Barenne
  - "Factors of Facilitation and Extinction in the Central Nervous System", 1939; 1 item; J. G. Dusser de Barenne
  - "Factors Limiting the Maximum Impulse Transmitting Ability of an Afferent System of Nerve Fibres", 1956; 3 items; P. D. Wall, J.Y. Lettvin, and W.H. Pitts
  - "Figures and Legends of How the Brain Works", 1 item
    Used in course work?
  - "Final Grant Report" to NIH, 1963; 4 items
  - "Finality and Form in Nervous Activity", 1946-1958; 3 folders
    James Arthur Lecture, 1946
  - "Fiorello", 1967; 1 item; Roberto Moreno-Diaz
  - [First lecture on Physiology of Knowledge], n.d.; 3 items
  - "Functional Activity and pH of the Cerebral Cortex", 1937; 1 item; J. G. Dusser de Barenne, Johannes Gregorius, and Leslie F. Nims
  - "Functional Boundaries in the Sensori-Motor Cortex of the Monkey, 1936; 1 item; J. G. Dusser de Barenne
  - "Functional Interdependence of Sensory Cortex and Thalamus., 1940, 1941; 2 items; J. G. Dusser de Barenne
  - "Functional Organization and Interrelation of Cerebral Hemispheres in Monkey", 1941; 1 item; Garol, Hugh W.
  - "Functional Organization in the Face-Subdivision of the Sensory Cortex of the Monkey (Macaca Mulatta)", 1938; 1 item; J. G. Dusser de Barenne
  - "Functional Organization in the Sensory Cortex of the Monkey (Macaca Mulatta)", 1938; 1 item; J. G. Dusser de Barenne
  - "Functional Organization of Frontal Pole in Monkey and Chimpanzee", 1944; 1 item; Margaret Kennard
  - "Functional Organization of Temorpal Lobe of Monkey (Macaca Mulatta) and Chimpanzee (Pan Satyrus), 1943; 1 item; Percival Bailey, Gerhardt von Bonnin, Edward Davis, Hugh W. Garol, Ephraim Roseman, and Anibal Silveira
  - "The Functional Organization of the Cerebral Cortex", 1944; 1 item
  - "Functional Organization of the Medial Aspect of the Primate Cortex", 1944; 1 item; Percival Bailey, Gerhardt von Bonnin, Edward Davis, Hugh W. Garol, Ephraim Roseman, and Anibal Silveira
  - "The Functional Organization of the Occipital Lobe", 1942; 1 item; Gerhardt von Bonin and Hugh W. Garol
  - "Further Observations on Associational Pathways in the Brain of Macaca Mulatta", 1944; 1 item; Percival Bailey, Gerhardt von Bonnin, Edward Davis, Hugh W. Garol, Ephraim Roseman, and Anibal Silveira
  - "Generalization, Analysis, and Induction" or "Knower, Known, and Knowledge Analylical", 2 items
  - "Gratuitous Changes in the Central Nervous System", 1947; 1 item; J.R. Klein and N.S. Olsen
  - "Historical Introduction to the Postulational Foundations of Experimental Epistemology", 1962; 8 items
  - "Head Injuries", 1932; 1 item; S. Bernard Wortis
  - "A Heterarchy of Values Determined by the Topology of Nervous Nets", 1945; 1 item
  - "A Heterarchy of Values Determined by the Topology of Nervous Nets", 1945; 1 item
    Letter to the editor
  - "How Brains Work", 1962; 3 items
  - "How Good is Your Memory?", 1941; 3 items
    Lecure, GE Research Laboratory Colloquiam, 1941
  - "How Nervous Structures Have Ideas.", 1949; 1 item; Walter Pitts
    Lecture, American Neurological Association, 1949
  - "How Seen Movement Appears in the Frog's Optic Nerve, Part I", 1959; 1 item; Humberto R. >Maturana, J. Y. Lettvin, and W. H. Pitts
  - How We Know Universals:The Perception of Auditory and Visual Forms", 1947; 1 item; Walter Pitts
  - "How We See Shape", n.d.; 1 item
  - "The Human Brain", [1960?]; 12 items
    Fair copy with photographs of figures. Printed in Microelectronic Engineering?
  - "The Human Brain", 1960; 3 items
    Lecture delivered at several West Coast institutions
  - "The Imitation of One Form of Life by Another - Biomimesis", 1962; 1 item
  - "Influence of Ether Narcosis on pH of Cortex and Electrocorticogram", 1939; 1 item; L. F. Nims and J. G. Dusser de Barenne
  - "Information in the Head", 1956; 2 items
  - "Information Processing in the Central Nervous System with Special Reference to the Reticular System", 1969; 1 item; William L. Kilmer
  - "Information Selection and Procesing in Visual Systems.", 1968; 3 items
    Envelope indicates "there is a tape of this lecture."
  - "Inhibition of Impulses Traveling in the Primary Afferent Dorsal Column Fibers of Cat Spinal Cord", 1954; 1 item; J. Y. Lettvin, P. D. Wall, B. Howland, and W. H. Pitts
  - "Insights into Neuronal Closed Loops from Shift Register Theory.", n.d.; 1 item; José S. da Fonseca
  - "Integration of the Nervous System and Feed-back Mechanism", 1953; 3 items
    Lecture, Army Medical Service Graduate School, Basic Sciences Course, 1952
  - "Integrative Aspects of the Nervous System.", 1949; 1 item; Leon Eisenberg.
    General Basic Science, 1949
  - "Introduction to the Problem of the Reticular Formation", 1966; 2 items; William L. Kilmer
  - "Introductory Remarks", 1955; 1 item
    Appeared in: Transactions of the 10th Conference on Cybernetics, sponsored by the Josiah Macy, Jr. Foundation, April 22-24, 1955
  - "I. pronounced 'eye'", n.d.; 1 item
    Lecture at the Chicago Literary Society
  - "Irreversibility of Conduction in the Reflex Arc", 1938; 1 item
  - "Johannes Gregorius Dusser de Barrenne (1885-1940)", 1 item